# KASHISH KHARBANDA

A self-driven digital native carrying a high level of enthusiasm for Information Technology and Entrepreneurship. Well-versed with Computer Science and Data Science principles. 4 years of tutoring experience in the CS landscape, 3 years of experience interning in the industry, 2 years of experience in leadership roles. Growth minded with a vision of creating an impact. A people person looking for opportunities that leverage strong leadership and collaborative skills!

# Contact

**Greater Seattle Area** 

(404) 518-0072

🔽 kashishkhar@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/kashishk/
kashishkhar.github.io/profile/

# **Skills**

### **Professional**

Leadership
Willingness to learn
Adaptability
Dependability
Time Management

Technical
Java
Python
Pandas, Numpy, MatPlotLib
Technology Blogging
SQL, PostrgeSQL
Git
Cloud, Data Migration
MS Office

# **Education**

#### University of California, Berkeley Aug 2019 - May 2023

Computer Science, Data Science Certificate of Entrepreneurship&Tech

#### Relevant coursework:

- Structure/Interpretation of Computer Programs
- Data Structures
- o Foundations of Data Science
- Principles/Techniques of Data
   Science
- Designing Information Devices and Systems (I & II)
- o Introduction to Entrepreneurship

#### **North Creek High School**

Sep 2017 - June 2019

High School Diploma

**Organizations:** Future Business Leaders of America, Technology Student Association, HOSA, Girls Who Code, American Cancer Society, Google NCWIT

# **Experience**

### **Data Science Research Mentor**

Undergrad Laboratory @ Berkeley

Sep 2020-present

Research mentor in Data Science division; responsible for leading and mentoring 4-5 students for research project being presented in May 2021.

### **External Events & Partnerships**

**Opportunity Through Data** 

Sep 2020-present

Part of strategic operations team with the vision of improving access to Data Science education, particularly in underrepresented communities.

#### Committee Member

FEMTech @ Berkelev

Sep 2019-present

2019 | Managed financial sector of club (budgeting, reimbursements). 2020 | Hosting career-related events for females in Technology/STEM.

### **Summer Extern**

AT&T

Jun 2020-Aug 2020

Certified for 80 hours of IT, Business, and Professional Development training.

### **AI Platform Intern**

**Microsoft Corporation** 

June 2019-August 2019

Used Python and SQL to understand the unexpected change of data features overtime and learned how to address the resulting model accuracy degradation.

### **Data Science Intern**

**Microsoft Corporation** 

Jun 2018-Aug 2018

Worked on Data Migration and SKU Recommendation to predict the best Azure SQL Database SKU for an on-premises database; used Python, C#, SQL, U-SQL in Azure Data Lake, and PostgreSQL.

#### Founder & President

FBLA @ North Creek High School

Sep 2017-Jul 2018

Founded school's FBLA chapter by establishing the chapter's authenticity and legacy. Led more than 100 members as President.

# **Projects**

#### **Stock Market Prediction**

In Progress

As part of UC Berkeley's Data Science Society, used a 64-feature Open High Low Close stock market dataset for 10 NASDAQ-100 companies to extract the technical indicators needed to predict stock market trends.

#### **Facial Detection**

June 2020

Learned about Computer Vision and utilized Machine Learning based Haar Cascade classifiers with Adaboost to identify objects in images and videos, particularly human facial features.

## **Inclusive Meeting**

July 2019

Used Natural Language Processing to perform sentimental analysis on team meeting conversations and gauge certain factors such as tone of speaker, productivity of meeting, etc. Also learned about data privacy.

# **Activities & Awards**

- **Juni Learning** | CS instructor for Python, Java, and AP CS [present]
- Google NCWIT | Award recipient
- Mobile Application Development | Top 15 at FBLA Nationals
- Relay for Life cancer nonprofit | Team captain, Social Media Lead
- Girls Who Code | Volunteer and Tutor